A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Social Service records, Personnel, Series 5 FA807
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Social Service records, Personnel, Series 5
1936-1951
Rockefeller Archive Center
James, Henry, Jr.
Jacobs, Walter A. (Walter Abraham), 1883-1967
Flinn, Waldo R.
Rockefeller University
Pearce, Louise, b. 1886
Flexner, Simon
Barus, Maxwell
Norris, James U.
Greene, Jerome D.
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
Smith, Edric Brooks
Cogger, John W.
Brown, Wade H.
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA807
9 Box(es)
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 212-5
Arrangement note
The Assistant Business Manager records are arranged in multiple series:
Series 2: Correspondence
Series 3: Subject Files
Series 5: Social Service Records
Conditions Governing Access note
Series 5: Restricted.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Other Finding Aids
FA013 Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Subject Files, Series 3
FA806 Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Correspondence, Series 2
Health insurance; Tryparsamide; Patent medicines; Vivisection; Civil defense; Wages -- Accounting; James, Henry, Jr.; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. War Demonstration Hospital; Jacobs, Walter A. (Walter Abraham), 1883-1967; Flinn, Waldo R.; Rockefeller University; Pearce, Louise, b. 1886; Flexner, Simon; Barus, Maxwell; Norris, James U.; Greene, Jerome D.; Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975; Smith, Edric Brooks; Merck & Co; Cogger, John W.; Brown, Wade H.; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Social Service Records, 1936-1951; 5; 9 Box(es)
  Biographical/Historical note
  During the early years of the RIMR, personnel matters were handled by the business manager. After the end of Simon Flexner's tenure as director, and with the arrival of Waldo Flinn as assistant business manager, the assistant business manager's office began to manage these matters. In 1955, a personnel supervisor was appointed.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged chronologically and alphabetically within each group of years.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restricted from scholarly access: Personnel records.
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes payroll information forms, medical examination of applicant forms, as well as memoranda and correspondence.
  - A-C, 1936-1944 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from scholarly access - personnel records.
  - T-Z, 1947-1951 (Box 1)
  - D-K, 1936-1944 (Box 2)
  - L-R, 1936-1944 (Box 3)
  - S-Z, 1936-1944 (Box 4)
  - A-Z, 1945 (Box 5)
  - A-D, 1947-1951 (Box 6)
  - E-J, 1947-1951 (Box 7)
  - K-M, 1947-1951 (Box 8)
  - N-S, 1947-1951 (Box 9)